<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="sect-Desktop">
  <title>Desktop</title> 
  <para />

  <section id="desktop-cinnamon">
    <title>Cinnamon Spin</title>
    <para>
     The Cinnamon desktop version 2.6 is now available as a Spin for Fedora 23. Cinnamon is a modern desktop environment based on the GNOME Shell, with advanced features and a traditional and flexible user experience.
    </para>
    <para>Updates and improvements in this release include: 
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para> Improved multi-monitor support 
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para> HTML5 and XScreenSaver support for animated screensavers 
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para> Panel management improvements 
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para> New inhibit applet to hide notifications and temporarily suspend power saving events 
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para> Redesigned system settings panel for improved usability 
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para> Accessibility improvements, including better support for ATK/Orca, magnifiers, and and a new On-Screen Keyboard applet 
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para> See the <ulink url="http://cinnamon.linuxmint.com/">Cinnamon official website</ulink>  for more information on Cinnamon, and go to <ulink url="http://spins.fedoraproject.org">http://spins.fedoraproject.org</ulink> to download the Spin. 
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="desktop-GNOME">
		<title>GNOME</title>
		<para>Fedora 23 will feature the latest available version of Gnome - 3.18. More information on Gnome 3.18 can be found here: <ulink url="https://wiki.gnome.org/ThreePointSeventeen/ReleaseNotes">https://wiki.gnome.org/ThreePointSeventeen/ReleaseNotes</ulink>.</para>
	
  </section>
  <section id="desktop-sugar">
    <title>Sugar</title>
    <para>Originally started as part of the One Laptop per child initiative, Sugar is a desktop environment targeted for children ages 5 - 12 to provide learning and educational activities through rich media. Sugar is the core component of a worldwide effort to provide every child with the opportunity for a quality education. 
    </para>
    <para>This update to sugar 0.106 includes the following: 
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para> improved performance 
	</para>
      </listitem>
       <listitem>
	<para> updated activities 
	</para>
       </listitem>
        <listitem>
	<para> New social help for access to discussion forums and collaborative learning 
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>See the <ulink url="http://wiki.sugarlabs.org/go/0.106/Notes">SugarLabs release notes</ulink> for more information on this sugar release.

    </para>
  </section>
</section>

