<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Editions-Server">
    <title>Fedora Server</title>

    <section id="server-roles">
        <title>Fedora Server Roles</title>
        <para>
	  A Featured Server role is an installable component of Fedora Server that provides a well-integrated service on top of the Fedora Server platform. These prepared roles simplify deployment and management of a service compared to setting up an upstream server from scratch; their use is recommended but optional; existing users of upstream servers based on Fedora RPMs will not be impeded.
  </para>
  <para>
    For kickstart installations, you can use the <package>Fedora Server</package> environment group to deploy Server.
  </para>

        <section id="Domain-Controller-Server-Role">
            <title>Domain Controller Server Role</title>
            <para>
                Fedora Server can deploy a domain controller powered by FreeIPA. The role greatly simplifies configuration of a primary domain controller.
            </para>
            <para>
                When combined with SSSD, complex tasks such as single-sign-on and authenticated access to network resources is easily accomplished.
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="Database-Server-Role">
      <title>Database Server Role</title>
        <para>
          Rapidly deploy instances of the powerful <application>postgresql</application> database server using the new Database Server Role for rolekit.
        </para>
        <!-- Instructions needed -->
    </section>

    <section id="Cockpit-Management-Console">
        <title>Cockpit Management Console</title>
        <para>
            The <application>Cockpit Management Console</application> (the <package>cockpit</package> package) is available by default in Fedora Server. This tool provides a powerful, easy to use, web-based graphical interface for managing multiple Linux servers. Features include:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <systemitem>systemd</systemitem> service management
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Journal log viewer
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Storage configuration including LVM
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>Docker</application> container management
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Basic network configuration
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Adding and removing local users
                </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <para>
            Any user known to the server can log in to the <application>Cockpit</application> console by opening <systemitem class="ipaddress" >http://<replaceable>server-ip-address</replaceable>:9090</systemitem>.
          </para>
		</section>

</section>
